Finding Aid for School of Education (University of Michigan) Records, 1904-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Dean's Files
  - Stark, Joan S., 1930-1988; 1978-1983
    - Fall Lecture Series, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Federal Legislation, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Fees and Charges, 1975-1982 (Box 26)
    - Financial Aid, 1955-1981 (Box 26)
    - Firsts, School of Education, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Flint Campus, 1980-1982
      - Yearly Reports, 1970-1977 (Box 26)
    - Fresh Air Camp
      - General, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Budget Materials, 1968-1979 (Box 26)
      - Executive Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 26)
    - Future Planning, 1979-1980 (Box 26)
    - Gerontology, Institute of, 1980-1983 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Employee Organization, 1980-1982 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Student Aid, Report of Task Force on, 1983 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Student Assistants, 1980-1982 (Box 26)
    - Grievance Procedures, 1980-1983 (Box 26)
    - Guidance and Counseling Program
      - General, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Alumni and Student Support Group, 1982 (Box 26)
      - Rehabilitation Projects, 1978-1979 (Box 26)
    - Hazen Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 26)
    - Higher Education, Center for the Study of (Box 27)
      - General, 1979-1982; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Minutes, 1979-1981 (Box 27)
      - Graduate Materials, 1976-1981 (Box 27)
    - Hinsdale Award, 1939-1971 (Box 27)
    - Historical Materials, 1959-1970 (Box 27)
    - Hospital School, 1962-1967 (Box 27)
    - Human Adjustment, Institute for
      - General, 1975-1979 (Box 27)
      - Resource booklet, 1978 (Box 27)
    - ISMRRD (Box 27)
      (SEE-Mental Retardation an Related Disabilities, Institute for the Study of)
    - Institute for Social Research (ISR), 1980-1983 (Box 27)
      (includes minutes)
    - Instructional and Institutional Issues, 1980-1983; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Instructional Strategies Services
      - General, 1980-1983; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Advisory Committee Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 27)
    - International Year of the Child
      - General, 1979 (Box 27)
      - Monograph, 1979 (Box 27)
    - Joint Appointments, 1979-1983 (Box 27)
    - Journals (that faculty have published in), 1973-1982 (Box 27)
    - Kellogg Foundation, 1979-1983 (Box 27)
    - Library (university), 1980-1982 (Box 27)
    - Library Committee, 1979/1980 (Box 27)
    - Library Science, 1970-1983 (Box 27)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of
      - General, 1980-1983 (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous Teaching Statistics, 1979-1980 (Box 27)
    - "M" Program, 1979 (Box 27)
      (educational and community development)
    - Mainstreaming
      - General, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Proposal for Continuation, 1980 (Box 28)
    - Manpower Leadership Program, 1975-1978 (Box 28)
    - Marguerite Wilker Johnson Awards, 1979-1983 (Box 28)
    - Master's Degree Sequences in Education, 1982 (Box 28)
    - Memorandum of Understanding, 1978 (Box 28)
      (between SOE and Office of Academic Affairs)
    - Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities, Institute for the Study
      - General, 1980-1982; 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 28)
    - Metropolitan Detroit Bureau of Social Studies (MDBSS)
      - General, 1966-1980 (Box 28)
      - Agreement and Bylaws, 1948-1981 (Box 28)
      - Budget, 1977-1983 (Box 28)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 28)
      - Executive Board Minutes, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Michigan Association of Colleges of Teacher Education,1980-1981 (Box 28)
    - Michigan Department of Education, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Michigan Society of Fellows, 1978-1983 (Box 28)
    - Minorities, 1980-1982 (Box 28)
    - Minority Affairs, Office of (OSMA-School of Education)
      - General
        - 1980 (Box 28)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 28)
      - Budget, 1971-1980 (Box 28)
    - Minority Enrollment., 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - Multicultural Education, 1980-1983 (Box 28)
    - National Alliance of Black School Educators, 1980 (Box 29)
    - National Council for Accreditation of Teachers Education (NCATE)
      - General, 1980-1981 (Box 29)
      - Self Study
        - 1963 (Box 29)
        - 1972 (Box 29)
        - 1973 (Box 29)
        - 1983 (Box 48)
      - Site Visit
        - 1982 (Box 29)
        - 1983 (Box 29)
      - Team Visitation Report
        - 1974 (Box 29)
        - 1983, 2 folders (Box 29)
        - 1983, 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Quantitative Data Summary, 1972-1973 (Box 29)
      - Team Visitation Report
        - 1974 (Box 29)
    - North Central Accreditation (self study), 1979-1980 (Box 29)
    - Occupational Education Program
      - 1980, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - 1982 (Box 29)
    - Organizational Studies Seminar, 1981 (Box 29)
    - Phi Kappa Phi (honor society), 1962-1981 (Box 29)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, 1960-1974 (Box 29)
      (professional fraternity for men in education)
    - Physical Education
      - General
        - 1980 (Box 29)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 29)
        - 1982-1983 (Box 29)
      - Minutes, 1979-1983 (Box 29)
      - Kinesiology (request for name change), 1981 (Box 29)
      - Physical Therapy Transition Proposal, 1981 (Box 29)
      - Review Committee, 1967-1977 (Box 29)
      - Undergraduate Admissions, 1980-1981 (Box 29)
    - Pi Lambda Theta (professional honor organization for women in education), 1964-1981 (Box 30)
    - Primary Research Staff, 1978 (Box 30)
    - Professional Development Centers (for teachers), 1978-1982 (Box 30)
    - Professional Development
      - General
        - 1981 (Box 30)
        - 1982-1983 (Box 30)
      - Committee, 1982/1983 (Box 30)
    - Professional Organizations (faculty membership), 1978-1982 (Box 30)
    - Program for Educational Opportunity (PEO), 1982 (Box 30)
    - Project Choice, 1978-1979 (Box 30)
    - Project Community, 1978-1983 (Box 30)
    - Promotions
      - General, 1977-1982; 7 folders (Box 43)
      - Faculty A-Z, 1979-1983; 15 folders (Box 43)
    - Publications Office
      - Bulletin, 1976-1982 (Box 30)
      - Innovator, 1978-1982 (Box 30)
      - Policies, 1978-1980 (Box 30)
    - Reading Program, 1980-1983 (Box 30)
    - Rehabilitation Counselor Education Program, 1974-1982 (Box 30)
    - Reorganization
      - General, 1982 (Box 30)
      - Advisory Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 30)
      - Director of Teacher Education, 1982 (Box 30)
      - Faculty Assignments, 1982 (Box 30)
      - New Units, 1982 (Box 30)
      - Preliminary Proposals, 1982 (Box 30)
      - Unit Chairs, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Report
      - The School of Education: 50 Year Report, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Research Activities, 1980-1981 (Box 30)
    - Sabbatical Leaves, 1978-1984 (Box 30)
    - Scholarly Work, Report of, 1981 (Box 30)
    - School Districts in Michigan (Upper Peninsula), 1979-1980 (Box 30)
    - Schoolmasters Club Scholarship, 1960-1982 (Box 30)
    - Shady Trails, 1978-1983 (Box 30)
    - Shaw College, 1972-1981 (Box 30)
    - Sheffield Exchange Program, 1962-1983 (Box 30)
    - Smart Foundation, 1972-1977 (Box 30)
    - Social Foundations Program, 1980-1982 (Box 30)
    - Society for College and University Planning (SCUP), 1979-1983 (Box 30)
    - Special Education
      - 1980 (Box 31)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 31)
    - Speech and Hearing Sciences
      - General
        - 1980-1981 (Box 31)
        - 1982 (Box 31)
      - Communications Disorders Clinic, 1978-1981 (Box 31)
      - Course Work and Curriculum, 1978-1981 (Box 31)
    - Spencer Foundation Seed Grant Program
      - General
        - 1980 (Box 31)
        - 1981 (Box 31)
        - 1982-1983 (Box 31)
      - Proposals, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Staffing Priorities, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Standing Committee Memberships, 1953-1982 (Box 31)
    - Student Faculty Assembly, 1970-1972 (Box 31)
    - Students for Educational Innovation (SEI), 1980-1982 (Box 31)
    - Teacher Education, Division of
      - General
        - 1980 (Box 31)
        - 1981 (Box 31)
        - 1982 (Box 31)
      - Minutes, 1980-1983 (Box 31)
    - Teacher Supply/Demand/Placement
      - 1980-1981 (Box 31)
      - 1981-1983 (Box 31)
    - Teaching English as a Second Language, 1978-1982 (Box 31)
    - Tenure, 1972-1979 (Box 31)
    - Thurnau Endowment, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Undergraduate Certification Manual, 1982 (Box 31)
    - University School
      - General, 1954-1972 (Box 31)
      - Meeting with President Robbin Fleming, 1970 (Box 31)
    - Wilbur J. Cohen Award, 1978 (Box 31)
    - William H. Payne Scholar Award, 1938; 1971 (Box 31)
    - Yearly Schedule of Activities, 1980-1982 (Box 31)
    - Z Form (revision), 1980 (Box 31)
    - Zimbabwe Proposal, 1981-1982 (Box 31)
    - School of Education Review
      - Review Notes, 1982-1983 (Box 47)
      - Chronology of School of Education Review Written from Joan Stark's Notes and Files, 1983 (Box 47)
    - Speeches
      - 1976-1982, 4 folders (Box 47)
      - 1978-1986 (Box 47)
      - Teacher Education Speeches, 1978-1979 (Box 47)
  - Berger, Carl F., 1958-1988; 1983-1988
    The files of Carl F. Berger (11 linear feet) span the years 1958-1988, although the bulk covers primarily the tenure of Berger, 1983-1988. The records document the activities of and changes in the School as a result of the reorganization following the 1982-83 review. The many centers and offices are represented in detail, allowing for a good comparison with the School during the tenure of Dean Stark. In addition, the Graduate Division is very well documented through the minutes of the Graduate Affairs Committee. All reports are located under the heading "Reports" and primarily evaluate the post-review activities of the School.
    - Academic Services, Office of
      - 1983 (Box 32)
      - 1984 (Box 32)
      - 1985 (Box 32)
      - 1986, 2 folders (Box 32)
      - 1986 (Box 32)
      - 1987 (Box 32)
      - 1988 (Box 32)
    - Accreditation, 1984-1986 (Box 32)
    - Admissions
      - 1983-1984 (Box 32)
      - (graduate), 1985-1986 (Box 32)
      - (graduate), 1987 (Box 32)
      - 1988 (Box 32)
    - Affirmative Action
      - General, 1987-1988 (Box 32)
      - Faculty Cohort Study, 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Alumni, 1988 (Box 32)
    - Annual Awards Ceremony, 1989 (Box 32)
    - Baccalaureate Degree, 1987 (Box 32)
    - Bilingual Education, 1984 (Box 32)
    - Budget
      - 1923-1950 (Box 32)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 32)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 32)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 32)
      - 1988 (Box 32)
    - Bureau of Accreditation and School Improvement Services (BASIS)
      - General
        - 1983-1985 (Box 32)
        - 1986 (Box 32)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 32)
      - Historical Materials, 1969-1976 (Box 32)
      - Self Study, 1987 (Box 32)
    - Bureau of School Services, 1982; 3 folders (Box 32)
      (from SOE Review exhibits 130-132)
    - Campaign for Michigan, 1985 (Box 32)
    - Celebration '87, 1986-1987 (Box 32)
    - Center for Educational Technology, 1988 (Box 33)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Schooling, 1985-1988 (Box 33)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (CRLT)
      - 1983-1986 (Box 33)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 33)
    - Center for the Study of Higher and Presecondary Education (CSHPE)
      - 1983-1985 (Box 33)
      - 1986-1988 (Box 33)
    - Certification
      - 1983-1985, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - 1986 (Box 33)
      - 1987 (Box 33)
    - China-Related Activities, 1979-1984 (Box 33)
    - Cohen Symposium, 1987/88 (Box 33)
    - Collegiate Institute for Values and Science, 1983-1986 (Box 33)
    - Combined Program in Education and Psychology (CPEP)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 33)
      - 1985-1987 (Box 33)
      - 1988 (Box 33)
    - Committees
      - Alumni Visiting Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 33)
      - Ann Arbor Public Schools/University of Michigan Research Review Committee, 1981-1987 (Box 33)
      - Appraisal Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 33)
      - Curriculum Committee
        - 1979/80 (Box 33)
        - 1980/81 (Box 33)
      - Curriculum Coordinating Committee, 1984 (Box 33)
      - Dissertation Committee
        - 1983-1984 (Box 33)
        - 1985-1986 (Box 33)
      - Educational Technology Committee, 1984 (Box 33)
      - Graduate Affairs Committee
        - 1958-1960 (Box 33)
        - 1960-1962 (Box 33)
        - 1962-1966 (Box 33)
        - 1966-1968 (Box 33)
        - 1979/80 (Box 33)
        - 1980/81 (Box 34)
        - 1981/82
          - Minutes (Box 34)
          - Admissions (Box 34)
          - Background Materials (Box 34)
          - Charge to the Committee (Box 34)
          - Curriculum Change, 4 folders (Box 34)
          - Background Materials (Box 34)
          - Charge to the Committee (Box 34)
          - Curriculum Change, 4 folders (Box 34)
          - Dissertation Quality (Box 34)
          - Graduate Credit Guidelines (Box 34)
          - Merit Awards (Box 34)
          - Petitions (Box 44A)
          - Research Competency (Box 34)
        - 1982/83
          - Minutes (Box 34)
          - Background Material (Box 34)
          - Dissertation Quality (Box 34)
          - General (Box 34)
          - Merit Awards (Box 34)
          - Petitions (Box 44A)
          - New/Experimental Courses (Box 34)
          - Research Competency (Box 34)
        - 1983/84
          - Minutes (Box 34)
          - Background Material (Box 34)
          - Petitions (Box 44A)
        - 1985
          - Minutes
            - April (Box 34)
            - May (Box 34)
            - September (Box 34)
            - October (Box 34)
            - November (Box 34)
            - December (Box 34)
          - Petitions (Box 44A)
        - 1986
          - Minutes
            - January (Box 34)
            - February (Box 34)
            - March (Box 34)
            - April (Box 34)
            - May (Box 34)
            - June (Box 34)
            - July (Box 34)
            - August (Box 35)
            - September (Box 35)
            - October-December (Box 35)
          - Petitions, 5 folders (Box 44A)
          - Report
            - Improving Dissertation Quality: A Report of the Graduate Affairs Committee, 1986 (Box 35)
        - 1987
          - Minutes, 6 folders (Box 35)
          - By-Laws (Box 35)
          - Minutes, 6 folders (Box 35)
          - By-Laws (Box 35)
          - Curriculum Actions (Box 35)
          - Log of Dissertation Committee (Box 35)
          - Petitions, 4 folders (Box 44A)
            [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2017 ]
          - Minutes with Graduate Student Evaluations (Box 44A)
            [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2062 ]
        - 1988
          - Minutes, 3 folders (Box 35)
          - Curriculum Actions (Box 35)
          - Faculty Review (Box 44A)
            [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2018 ]
          - Petitions, 4 folders (Box 44A)
        - 1989
          - Minutes, 3 folders (Box 35)
          - Curriculum Actions (Box 35)
          - Dissertation Committees (Box 35)
          - Petitions, 4 folders (Box 45)
            [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2019 ]
          - Report -Improving Dissertation Quality (Box 35)
      - Instructional Technology Committee, 1981 (Box 35)
      - Professional Relations Development Committee, 1983/84 (Box 35)
      - Promotions Committee
        - 1984/85 (Box 45)
        - 1985/86 (Box 45)
      - Research/Human Subjects Review Committee
        - Minutes, 1978-1984; 5 folders (Box 35)
        - General, 1982-1984 (Box 35)
      - Student Grievance and Discipline Committee, 1981-1986 (Box 35)
      - Technology Task Force, 1983 (Box 35)
      - Undergraduate Certification Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 35)
    - Computers in Early Literacy (CIEL), 1987/88 (Box 35)
    - Computers, Educational Use of, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Consortium for Evaluation, Research, Training and Service (CERTS)
      - Memorandum of Understanding, 1979-1982 (Box 35)
      - Paper-"A Training/Dissemination Model" ca., 1986 (Box 35)
    - Core Courses
      - General, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Committee, 1985 (Box 35)
      - Educational Psychology, 1985 (Box 35)
      - Evaluation Report, 1986 (Box 35)
      - Requirements, 1983 (Box 35)
      - Subcommittee, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Council on Rehabilitation Education (CORE)-Accreditation Evaluation 1983-84, 1984 (Box 35)
    - Cross Cultural Research in Education, 1988 (Box 35)
    - Curriculum Planning, 1987 (Box 35)
    - Curriculum Task Force, 1984 (Box 35)
    - Curriculum Teaching and Psychological Studies (CTPS) (Box 36)
      - General
        - 1985 (Box 36)
        - 1986-1988 (Box 36)
        - 1986 (Box 36)
        - 1987 (Box 36)
        - 1988 (Box 36)
      - Minutes, 1986 (Box 36)
    - Dean Search, 1983 (Box 36)
    - Dean's Award for Academic Excellence, 1988 (Box 36)
    - Dean's Council, 1986-1987 (Box 36)
    - Deanship, 1987 (Box 36)
    - Detroit Math/Science Masters Degree Program, 1985 (Box 36)
    - Detroit Public Schools/University of Michigan Collaborative
      - General
        - 1984 (Box 36)
        - 1985 (Box 36)
        - 1986 (Box 36)
        - 1988 (Box 36)
      - Symposium Handbook, 1984 (Box 36)
    - Development, 1986-1987 (Box 36)
    - Development and Alumni Services, 1988 (Box 36)
    - Development Curriculum and Teaching, 1983-1984 (Box 36)
    - Dissertation
      - Orals
        - 1984 (Box 36)
        - 1985, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - 1986, 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Procedures, 1986 (Box 36)
      - Problems, 1985-1986 (Box 45)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2061 ]
      - Quality, 1984-1987 (Box 36)
      - Quality Control System, 1988 (Box 36)
    - Diversity Day, 1988 (Box 36)
    - Doctor of Education Distinction, 1984-1987 (Box 36)
    - Dynamic Credentialing Laboratory (DCL), proposal for, 1988 (Box 36)
    - Early Childhood Education, 1986-1988 (Box 36)
    - Eastern Michigan University-Proposed Doctoral Leadership Program, 1982-1988 (Box 36)
    - Education Research, 1984 (Box 36)
    - Educational Computing For Undergraduate Teaching Certification, 1986 (Box 36)
    - Educational Foundations, Policy Administration, 1984-1987 (Box 37)
    - Educational Psychology, 1984-1986 (Box 37)
    - Educational Technology, 1983-1986 (Box 37)
    - Educational Technology Research Collaborative (ETRC)
      - General, 1984-1986 (Box 37)
      - Retreat, 1984 (Box 37)
    - Elementary Education Committee, 1983-1987 (Box 37)
    - English and Education, 1979-1987 (Box 37)
    - Enrollment
      - 1983-1985 (Box 37)
      - 1986-1988 (Box 37)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan, 1987 (Box 37)
    - ERIC/CAPS
      - Clearing House, 1984-1988 (Box 37)
      - Proposal, 1986/87 (Box 37)
    - Ethics and Values Workshop, 1988 (Box 37)
    - Evaluation Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 37)
    - Extension Service, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Appointments, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Awards, 1988 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Budget, 1982/83 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Development, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Information Manual, 1982 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Publications (list of), 1986 (Box 37)
    - Faculty Workload, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - Ferris State College, 1980-1985 (Box 37)
    - Financial Aid
      - 1983 (Box 37)
      - 1984 (Box 37)
      - 1985 (Box 37)
      - 1986 (Box 37)
      - 1987 (Box 37)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 1977-1985 (Box 37)
    - Fresh Air Camp, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Funded Research Projects (guidelines), 1989 (Box 37)
    - Gerontology, Institute of, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - Gifts, 1985-1988 (Box 37)
    - Governing Faculty, 1988-1989 (Box 37)
    - Graduate Applicants, 1988 (Box 38)
    - Graduate Degree Sequence, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Graduate Employees Organization (GEO), 1987 (Box 38)
    - Graduate Student Aid Task Force, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Graduate Student Assistants
      - 1984-1987 (Box 38)
      - 1988 (Box 38)
    - Graduate Student Assistantships, 1983-1986 (Box 38)
    - Grant Activity, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Green Hills School, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Grievances
      - Faculty
        - Smith, 1985-1986 (Box 45)
        - Speech & Language Pathology, 1982-1987; 2 folders (Box 46)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2017 ]
      - Student, 1980-1987 (Box 46)
    - Guidance and Counseling, 1984 (Box 38)
    - Higher and Adult Continuing Education (HACE)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 38)
      - (includes doctoral information), 1984-1985 (Box 38)
      - 1986 (Box 38)
      - 1987 (Box 38)
      - 1988 (Box 38)
    - Holmes Group, 1984-1987 (Box 38)
    - Horace Rackham School of Graduate Studies, 1984-1985 (Box 38)
    - Information Technology, 1985-1987 (Box 38)
    - Information Technology, Uses of, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Innovator, 1984-1987 (Box 38)
    - Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (ILIR), 1985 (Box 38)
    - Instructional Research and Information Systems (IRIS)
      - 1967-1983 (Box 38)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 38)
      - 1987 (Box 38)
      - 1988 (Box 38)
    - Instructional Technology
      - 1986-1987 (Box 38)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 38)
    - Interactive Communication Simulation (ICS), 1984-1988 (Box 38)
    - Journals (in which faculty have published), 1982 (Box 38)
    - Kellogg Foundation, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Legislature
      - 1984-1985 (Box 38)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 38)
    - Literacy Conference, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Michigan Department of Education (Box 39)
      - General, 1988 (Box 39)
      - Computer Science Certification, 1983-1986 (Box 39)
      - State Board Continuing Education Unit, 1987-1988 (Box 39)
    - Microcomputer Classroom/Lab, 1983-1985 (Box 39)
    - Microcomputer Education Center, 1984-1987 (Box 39)
    - Minorities, 1986-1987 (Box 39)
    - Minority Concerns, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Minority Enrollment and Recruitment in Teacher Education, 1985-1987 (Box 39)
    - Minority Students, 1988 (Box 39)
    - Mission Statement, 1980-1986 (Box 39)
    - National Center for Research to Improve Post Secondary Teaching and Learning (NCRIPTAL), 1987 (Box 39)
    - National Institute of Education (NIE)
      - General, 1983-1985 (Box 39)
      - Literacy Conference, 1984-1985 (Box 39)
    - National Science Foundation, 1987-1988 (Box 39)
    - Northwest Ordinance, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Occupational Education, 1981 (Box 39)
    - Office of Minority Student Affairs (OMSA, School of Education)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 39)
      - 1985-1987 (Box 39)
    - Paper-"The Teacher Preparation Institution; Addressing the Dynamic Relationships Between the School of Education and the University"-Carl Berger, 1986 (Box 39)
    - Peer Institutions, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Ph.D. in English Education, 1986-1987 (Box 39)
    - Ph.D. in Higher Education, 1983-1986 (Box 39)
    - Ph.D./Ed.D Differentiation, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Physical Education, Division of, 1984-1986 (Box 39)
    - Presidential Initiatives Fund, 1988 (Box 39)
    - Professional Development
      - 1983-1985 (Box 39)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 39)
    - Professional Development Credit, Proposal for, 1986 (Box 39)
    - Professional Organizations (faculty membership), 1986 (Box 39)
    - Program for Education Opportunity (PEO), 1984 (Box 39)
    - Project Save, 1986 (Box 39)
    - Promotions
      - General
        - 1982-1984 (Box 46)
        - 1984-1985 (Box 46)
      - Faculty
        - A-Z, 1984-1987; 8 folders (Box 46)
    - Publications Office, 1985-1986 (Box 39)
    - Racism, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Reading Lab, circa 1985 (Box 39)
    - Reading and Learning Skills Center, 1983-1985 (Box 39)
    - Recruitment
      - 1983-1984 (Box 39)
      - 1985 (Box 39)
      - 1986 (Box 39)
      - 1987 (Box 39)
    - Regents Fellowships, 1985-1987 (Box 39)
    - Regional Laboratory Design Committee, 1980 (Box 39)
    - Remedial Reading Clinic, 1985 (Box 39)
    - Reorganization (School of Education), 1985 (Box 39)
    - Reports
      - Academic Programs, Faculty Clusters, Degree Sequences and Integrating Themes, 1987 (Box 40)
      - Curriculum and Academic Programs in the School of Education 1985-86, 1986 (Box 40)